Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to program the output to compare functionality of the timer
and what output compare meters as you shall see us execute in a block of code.
When a particular timestamp arrives, we can basically we can have, um, let's say, four different
functions that we want to execute.
We want to execute one every hundred milliseconds.
And let's say we want to execute another one every five hundred milliseconds.
A third one every four hundred millisecond.
So are these particular timestamps.
We can execute our particular functions and we can achieve that by using the output to compare functionality
of the time as we want to see how to do that.
In this lesson.
So I'm going to create my new Cuba mixed project.
Right.
So this my new project, I start off by Clarinda and topping out, Claire helping out.
And then the regular stuff system call says the buck over here, serial wire on the RCC or bypass the
high speed external Lopez crystal resonator like this.
Okay, I'm gonna enable our LCD for this experiment as well.
P five over here on the set STPI you output.
I'll rename it to early.
Right.
So to demonstrate this, because I don't want to be connected, extend or LCD in extend or things to
my new clipboard.
I'm going to use that discovery board in this experiment because the discard report has for Eltis and
I can configure all four LCD for outpoll compare such the one to time auto or kiss that particular LCD
is just toggled.
Right.
So I'm gonna change my board.
I'm gonna come over here.
I'll say no.
I'm going to change to the Discovery Board.
And another reason for the Discovery Board is it has more peace.
All right.
Here we have 64 piece by the Discovery Board, has 100 pins, although he's the same microcontroller
by a bigger package.
Right.
So I'm going to change it.
And like I said, is the same microcontroller should work the same way across the concept.
Everything is the same.
So there shouldn't be anything but just for my demo, for me to demonstrate to you how output to compare
works.
I need, you know, a lot of multiple pins which have access to times.
So I'll do SDM 32 for.
One, one.
Oh, come over here to MCU selectable, and then I'll search or search the board.
SDM 32 for one one over here.
And then this is estimated to have for discovery.
So if you have just a nuclear abort, you can just watch a lock.
And I'm sure you would understand this.
It shouldn't be an issue.
So we go through the same process.
So when we get to a part where the, um, the nuclear hasn't got enough pings, we can use the disco
sense.
If you know how to program the SDM 32 for one, one is the same, is the same whether you have a pancake
with a hundred pins or a package with 64 pins.
You can see this is the desperate.
We've got 100 pins here.
And the disco has more things we can play with, more LCD, et cetera.
So I'm going to start over here by Claire and Claire and the pin out.
And then do our standard stuff, come over here says Zero Wire and then RACC.
We still gonna bypass this and then this CHRISTOULAS later.
Okay.
So our Eltis are connected to PD.
Fifteen people, fourteen PD 13, MPD twelve.
The Discovery Board has four Eltis.
I'm going to set all of these Eltis, all of these pins which of the Eltis to be hot to be in the outputs.
Um Yelp compared mode.
So we just use an LDS on example here.
If you have the nuclear board and you want a particular thing to or care during the time, or let's
say you have a particular, uh, let's see how the buzzer like a speaker that you want to make sound
every 50 milliseconds and then every two hundred seconds you want to start a DC motor.
In every 400 seconds, you want another output.
You can connect those outputs to the corresponding piece.
But I'm gonna use OLED to show here cause I have to do this cool boat, lightning round, so I'll come
over here.
Then I said this to time for S.H. for a speedy 15 and then time for then Tyber for an MPD twelve.
So we've got all of our four entities.
Right, that we have on the Discovery Board.
Okay.
So now we have to open the timer module and enable them as output compared with dealing with time off
for here as we see time for.
So time are for we using Chernow's.
One, two, three, four.
So of open channel time a for here to expand it.
OK, click over here.
So Channel one.
I'm gonna select.
Output.
Compare.
It's basically this one here article compare.
And then Channel two, article compare.
Channel three, article compare.
Channel four, outspoken pay as well.
So we've set all of our four channels here to compare.
Next, whenever we're using the time, we've got to provide a clock source.
I'm going to click here.
Internal clock.
So now we've got to set the parameters of our time as so offers divide by forty eight thousand.
And then over here, the counter period 1000 like this.
Now we've got to configure each channel.
So we've got Channel one here.
We have to set the demoed.
You click over here.
So we want toggle on much.
We wanted to toggle when the counter is on much.
So the pose, let's say counter one or channel one, we can say 200 M.
S, we can pass 200 over here.
Remember, this is the counter reload help inside out a thousand times, which is one second 200 M.
S.
We can change Channel two also to toggle on March and Channel two.
We can also see maybe something like 500 M.
S.
And then we have to know three.
We changed that also to talk alone much.
And then.
750 E.M.S..
And then we can say Channel four should togo every second.
So I'll pass 1000 here.
So then we have one fifth of a second half a second three fourth of a second and then one second.
Like this.
And then we can see article compare preload.
We can just enable this enable, enable and then enable.
So these players will be talking when the respective time stamps.
Okay.
So it's like controlling Hardware's different hardware devices connected to different players at specific
time periods.
Right.
So once we are done we can generate the, um, the code.
Okay.
Minimize this.
Come to project manager.
I'll give the project a name.
Toma output.
Compare.
Then I'll leave everything the same click over here to generate
before I generate.
I have to select my Kubi D actually.
Okay.
No I'll click to generate.
And then open a project.
So there's our project.
Oh, do the cleanup.
Okay.
Right.
So this will or may not see CFR looks like we've got a wild time, a handler.
We use in time afore we know that.
Right.
And we enable how and then system clock GPL you and then time of for.
So this time a four in its function.
This the code generated for us, given the um, the options we chose as well as the channels the day
period or the post we search for the channels.
If we want to update that we can change from code.
Over here we said two hundred for the first channel and then Channel two we said half a second.
Which is five hundred.
And then three fourths a second.
And then one second.
Right.
So output compares actually very straightforward.
The only thing we need to do is start the timer functions.
That's all we have to do.
So let's go to a what time a module and see the function we need in order to start the timer channels.
So come to drive us over here.
All drivers and then source and then time at of C, it's gonna say it wants to open in scalability mode.
Oh say do you want to change scalability settings.
No I do not.
And um the C.
Okay, so they function we're looking for is the output to compare thought.
So over here, this function is whole.
Oh, see in it initializes the timer output compay according to specialized parameters.
OK.
This the initializes the article compare.
So there's the function we need starts the timer output, compare signal generation it takes to document.
The first argument is the apparatus of the arm, the time of the time, a handler.
And then the next argument is that Cherno.
So we need this and we're gonna call this for each Cherno and it returns the, um.
Yeah.
The status typedef.
Copy this.
And then come to mean.
So we can simply paste on here and the first argument is, oh, what time are.
This one here?
That should be the address of it almost on here like this.
And then the cherno.
So let's start with China one.
We do time on a school, Cherno.
It has to be all Cupps TIAA.
And the school, China.
What can the school want?
Okay, so we have to do this for two, three and four one.
So over here we just change this to China.
To China with three.
And then channel four.
Like this.
So that's all we have to do, actually.
We can build.
It's appealed successfully.
Let's debug gets you onto the board.
So I just click over here to go to the debulked you.
Okay.
Okay, so click here to run.
It's running, but nothing is happening.
Oh, I see what's going on right over here.
Our preschooler has to be four thousand eight hundred.
I'm going to come over here.
Worth the time I in it.
We don't need to go back to Cuba, Max.
We can just change from here.
Right.
So I've just changed it.
Okay.
I'll click over here to build.
And then click here to go to the debugger.
And then click here to run.
And as you can see.
We have our ladies Torkel in India, all during which we configured.
However we miss in one.
We have four channels.
However, we have just three of them.
Torkel in um.
Let me see.
Right.
So this is our Cuba next generation.
And the reason we have in just three ladies blinkers, that's Channel four.
We've not changed the mode over here.
The mode has to be torgau toggle on much just like the others.
But I failed to change the mode.
That is why it is like this.
So I'm going to change it in a code.
So over here.
Time off for.
Let's see.
We come down here.
We'll see mode over here said, oh, see mode.
Okay.
So O.S. mode time in a search over here.
So I'm simply going to copy O.C. Mode Tokyo cause O.C. Mode, Torgau is the mode for everyone.
Either that or I can simply delete this line.
And this is important that you understand this because it's a structure right over here.
We said the O.C. Mode or C mode member to Tokyo.
So anything that we write applies or C more to toggle applies to everything until we change the mode
again.
So over here we changed it from oh Seymour to Tokyo.
So I can simply delete this without change.
Want to help in such that all of them would have also moved to Tokyo.
Right.
So I'm going to come out and then they would again.
Click over here to build.
To build.
It's appeals successfully, quickly to go to debug.
Okay.
And then click here to run.
I can see.
No, we have all four LCD torkel in.
Yeah, totally.
At the rate that we've said it's using in the upper house, the polls that we set in that specific order.
So this order is what is lesson.
If you have any questions, just live in the Q&A section and I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.